Guide to the Yale Art Gallery and Yale Center for British Art Recordings of Lectures and Presentations
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale University Art Gallery and the Yale Center for British Art, recordings of lectures and presentations
1950-2000
1987-2000
RU 359
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
20.25
The records consist of audio and video recordings of lectures, presentations and symposia held at the Yale Art Gallery and the Yale Center for British Art.
Yale University. Art Gallery
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 33-B (YRG 33-B), Records of the Yale Art Gallery.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of audio and video recordings of lectures, presentations and symposia held at the Yale Art Gallery and the Yale Center for British Art.
Art museums; Art; College art museums; Lectures and lecturing; Audiotapes; Videotapes; Yale Center for British Art; Yale University -- Museums; Yale University. Art Gallery
- Audio and video tapes of lectures and presentations at the Yale Art Gallery and the Center for British Art, circa 1950-1995; Accession 1998-A-056
  Scope and Contents
  The recordings are arranged by format in two sections: Audiocassettes and Video tapes. Some presentations are available in both formats and are therefore listed in both sections.
  - Audiocassettes
    - Aycock, Alice, 1991 April 11 (Box 1)
    - Danto, Arthur, 1992 (Box 2)
    - Demurth Symposium, "Declarations of Identity", 1994 October 7 (Box 3)
    - Demurth Symposium, "Declarations of Identity", 1994 October 7 (Box 4)
    - Demurth Symposium, "Declarations of Identity", 1994 October 7 (Box 5)
    - Demurth Symposium, "Declarations of Identity", 1994 October 7 (Box 6)
    - Demurth Symposium, "Declarations of Identity", 1994 October 7 (Box 7)
    - Elderfield, John, "Matisse's Feminine Representations", 1995 April 22 (Box 8)
    - Field, Richard, "Talk on Master Works", 1989 October 31 (Box 9)
    - Gilbert, Creighton, 1989 October 17 (Box 10)
    - Goldman, Martin, "Ossorio Tape on Pollock" Yale Art Gallery, 1978 November 5 (Box 11)
    - Harvey, Stephen, "Ahmose: Founder of The New Kingdom", 1994 October 12 (Box 12)
    - Irwin, Robert, "On the Nature of Abstraction" Yale Art Gallery., 1988 April 18 (Box 13)
    - Liedtke, Walter, "Rembrandt True and False", 1995 April 22 (Box 14)
    - Miller, Sara and Gregory Rocha, "South of the Border", 1993 (Box 15)
    - Montias, Michael, "The Art Market in the Dutch Republic in the 17thCentury", 1995 April 22 (Box 16)
    - Neill, Mimi, "Talk on Chinese", 1989 November (Box 17)
    - Newman, Sasha, "Masterworks: Highlights of the Gallery's Collection", 1989 November 7 (Box 18)
    - Oldenburg, "Van Brugein", 1991 April 25 (Box 19–20)
    - "Readings of Eugene O' Neill", 1994 October 16 (Box 21)
    - Romano, James, "Installation and Research: Insights into the Brooklyn Museum's New Galleries." Yale British Art Center, 1994 October 19 (Box 22)
    - Rose, Barbara, "Picasso's Roots in the Spanish Tradition", 1995 April 22 (Box 23)
    - Russman, Edna. Associate Fall series., 1994 October 5 (Box 24)
    - Scott, Gerry D., "The Lure of the Nile." British Art Center Art Gallery Associates Fall Lecture Series, 1994 October 26 (Box 25)
    - Shapiro, Joel, 1991 (Box 26)
    - Varnedoe, Kirk, 1991 April 4 (Box 27)
  - Video tapes
    - "African Dance and Music at Jabb's Pillow", 1987 (Box 28)
    - "Amistad" (very rough edit), undated (Box 29)
    - "AMS: Opening", undated (Box 30)
    - "African American Artists", 1994 (Box 31)
    - Ashley Bryant, "Portrait of a Storyteller." Yale University Art Gallery Education Department
      - Original, undated (Box 32)
      - Use copy, undated; videotape (VHS) (Box 32U)
    - Caro, Anthony in conversation with John Newman. Art Gallery., 1994 April 21 (Box 33)
    - Elderfield, John: "Matisse's Feminine Representations." Associate Spring Lectures, 1995 April 22 (Box 34)
    - Elderfield, John and Barbara Rose., 1994 April 22 (Box 35)
    - Elderfield, John and John Montiar. "Panel question and answer", undated (Box 36)
    - Frankenthaler
      - Original, April 29 (Box 37)
      - Use copy, April 29; videotape (VHS) (Box 37U)
    - Greenberg
      - Original, April 22 (Box 38)
      - Use copy, April 22; videotape (VHS) (Box 38U)
    - Harvey, Stephen, "Ahmose: Founder of the New Kingdom: Recent discoveries at Abydos"
      - Original, 1994 October 12 (Box 39)
      - Use copy, 1994 October 12; videotape (VHS) (Box 39U)
    - Hesse, Eva, "An excerpt from Four Artists: Robert Ryman, Eva Hesse, Bruce Nauman, Susan Rothenberg"
      - Original, 1992 March 9 (Box 40)
      - Use copy, 1992 June 30; videotape (VHS) (Box 40U)
    - Johnson, Lester (Location The Springs L. I. NewYork), 1950 (Box 41)
    - Kromer, Hilton, "The 60's: An End and a Beginning" Associate Spring Lecture Series
      - Original, 1994 April 7 (Box 42)
      - Use copy, 1994 April 7; videotape (VHS) (Box 42U)
    - Lewitt, Sol, 1992 April 22; Run time: 16 minutes 47 seconds (Box 43)
    - Lipstick X 4, undated (Box 44)
    - Liedtke, Walter, "Rembrandt: True or False?" Associate Spring Lecture #4
      - Original, 1995 April 22 (Box 45)
      - Use copy, 1995 April 22; videotape (VHS) (Box 45U)
    - "Looking at Renaissance Art," The Museum of Fine Arts Houston., 1990 (Box 46)
    - Miller, Sara and Gregory Rocha, "South of the Border.", 1993 (Box 46a)
    - Montias, Michael, "17thcentury patronage in Holland." Associate Spring Lectures. Lecture #1, 1995 April 22 (Box 47)
    - Noland, Kenneth in conversation with Karen Wilkin. Art Gallery., 1994 April 27 (Box 48)
    - Olitski, Jules Lecture. Associates Lecture Series. Art Gallery
      - Original, 1993 May 6 (Box 49)
      - Use copy, 1993 May 6; videotape (VHS) (Box 49U)
    - Poons, Larry Conversation with Jonathan Weinberg and Romy Goland. Art Gallery, 1994 April 14 (Box 50)
    - Romano, James: "Installation and Research: Insights into Brooklyn Museum's Galleries of Egyptian Art." British Art Center, 1994 October 19 (Box 51)
    - Rose, Barbara, "Picasso's Roots in the Spanish Tradition", 1995 April 22 (Box 51a)
    - Scott, Gerry D., "The Lure of the Nile: Organizing an Exhibition of Egyptian Art and Architecture", 1994 October 26 (Box 52)
    - Scott, Gerry, "The Lure of the Nile" and James Romano, "Brooklyn Museum's New Egyptian Art", 1994 October 26 (Box 52a)
    - Wilkin
      - Original, 1993 April 15 (Box 53)
      - Use copy, 1993 April 15; videotape (VHS) (Box 53U)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Catalog of Interactive Installations and Video: ACM SIGGRAPH '88 Exhibition of Computer Art., 1988; videotape (VHS) (Box 54)
    - Screenprint in the Making: Sondra Freckleton Collaborates with Norman Stewart in the Creation of the Fine Screenprint Entitled "Blue Chenille", 1985; videotape (VHS) (Box 55)
    - Welcome to the Wadsworth Antheneum, undated (Box 56)
- Audio and video tapes of the "On Their Work" symposium, 1997; Accession 1998-A-057
  Conditions Governing Access
  Original audio and videorecordings, as well as preservation masters and duplicating masters may not be played. Readers may only play use copies. If a use copy of a particular recording does not exist, researchers must consult with the reference archivist for policies and procedures regarding the creation of duplicating master and use copies of original recordings.
  - On their Work: Chuck Close only. Members Spring Symposium.
    - Original, 1997 April 26 (Box 1)
    - Use copy, 1997 April 26; videotape (VHS) (Box 1U)
  - On their Work: Michael Kimmelman panel discussion. Members Spring Symposium.
    - Original, 1997 April 26 (Box 2)
    - Use copy, 1997 April 26; videotape (VHS) (Box 2U)
    - Original, 1997 April 26 (Box 3)
    - Original, 1997 April 26 (Box 4)
  - On their Work: Frank Stella, Chuck Close, Michael Kimmelman. Members Spring Symposium.
    - Original, 1997 April 26 (Box 5)
    - Use copy, 1997 April 26; videotape (VHS) (Box 5U)
    - Original, 1997 April 26 (Box 6)
- Audio and video tapes of the "Looking Ahead" symposium, 1998; Accession 1999-A-012
  - Audio and videotapes of the symposium, "Looking Ahead: Issues for Museums in the 21st Century", 1998 (Box 1)
- Audiocassettes of symposium, 2000; Accession 2001-A-105
  Original audiorecordings, as well as preservation masters and duplicating masters may not be played. Readers may only play use copies. If a use copy of a particular recording does not exist, researchers must consult with the reference archivist for policies and procedures regarding the creation of duplicating master and use copies of original recordings.
  - Audiocassettes of symposium, "Members of the Yale Art Museum", 2000 April (Box 1)